<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data science in genetics &amp; related things</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data science in genetics &amp; related things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Sina Rueeger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 20:40:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with encryption of documents</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/2018-04-04-encryption-of-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 20:40:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/2018-04-04-encryption-of-files/</guid>
      <description>I work (broadly speaking) in epidemiology. Within collaborations we often have to share sensitive data across institutions and are therefore likely to not share IT facilities. But the most often used options - bare e-mail or file hosting - are not secure, as they both work via a server that could potentially be exposed.
There are a handful of secure options around (ProtonMail or keybase.io, both working via encryption), but for those that trust open source projects the most and are familiar with a terminal I have written some basic instructions for asymmetric GPG encryption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Per e-mail: sina.rueeger@gmail.com
Or via @sinarueeger on Keybase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My journey I studied Data Analysis &amp; Process Design at the School of Engineering in Winterthur, where I fell in love with applied statistics. I deepened my knowledge in statistical modelling with a Master&#39;s degree and by working as a research assistant. During my time as a biostatistician I enjoyed the interdisciplinary aspect and grew an interest in analysing genetic data - which ultimately lead me to my current position to Lausanne.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>