<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot2 on Sina Rüeger</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot2 on Sina Rüeger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LD Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/get-ld-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/get-ld-remotely/</guid>
      <description>Goal Two approaches Our toy data A solution that almost works: ensembl.org What reference panels / population can we choose from? Access LD between a SNP and its region Access LD matrix Access LD between a SNP and many other SNPs Colored locuszoom plot  2. Solutions that work half-through ldlink Using locuszoom software snpsnap API provided by sph.umich  3. Solution that does not work rsnps::ld_search  Session Info   The squared correlation between genetic markers is one way to estimate linkage disequilibrium (LD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locuszoom plot of GWAS summary statistics</title>
      <link>/post/locuszoomplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/locuszoomplot/</guid>
      <description>Goal Getting it done 1. Get summary statistics Visualising associations Identify genomic region with lowest P-value  2. Extracting annotation biomaRt Learning resources Using biomaRt Quick d-tour: assembly GRCh37 or GRCh38? Extracting gene name for one SNP Extracting gene names for genomic region  3. Combining summary statistics and annotation Wouldn’t it be nice… Source   In the world of genome-wide association studies (GWAS) we often get a list of genetic markers (SNPs) that seem for some reason relevant for a particular outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>