<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Analysing genetic data</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Analysing genetic data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Sina R&amp;uuml;eger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Locuszoom plot of GWAS summary statistics</title>
      <link>/2018/07/30/locuszoomplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/30/locuszoomplot/</guid>
      <description>1fd
In the world of genome-wide association studies (GWAS) we often get a list of genetic markers (SNPs) that seem for some reason relevant for a particular outcome. At the same time, we have little knowledge about these genetic variants that come in cryptic combinations of characters and numbers.
For example:
 We might get asked how frequent the SNP rs1421085 is in a range of populations.  We need to extract all known SNPs that are within 1 Mb of rs1421085.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locuszoom plot of GWAS summary statistics</title>
      <link>/2018/07/30/locuszoomplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/30/locuszoomplot/</guid>
      <description>1fd
In the world of genome-wide association studies (GWAS) we often get a list of genetic markers (SNPs) that seem for some reason relevant for a particular outcome. At the same time, we have little knowledge about these genetic variants that come in cryptic combinations of characters and numbers.
For example:
 We might get asked how frequent the SNP rs1421085 is in a range of populations.  We need to extract all known SNPs that are within 1 Mb of rs1421085.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>satRday Cardiff 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/07/04/satrday-cardiff-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 10:20:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/04/satrday-cardiff-2018/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief write-up of my satRdays Cardiff experience.
First - what is a satRday?
It is an awesome concept: attending an R conference organised by a local RUG on a Saturday.
The programme in Cardiff had parallel sessions - tough decision-making to pick between promising talks!
dplyr workshop Kathrine Tansey kept us busy with a workshop on dplyr in the morning.
💻 rstudio-cloud project
Packaging workshop Heather Turner upgraded us on packaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the Blogdown website</title>
      <link>/2018/04/14/setting-up-the-blogdown-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 10:00:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/14/setting-up-the-blogdown-website/</guid>
      <description>To set up this website I have used some excellent material around blogdown, github and hugo.
Motivation Before going into the technical details, let me say something about motivation and inspiration. For me, it definitely helped to read the blogpost by David Robinson, being encouraged by Ma&amp;euml;lle Salmon and seeing many others leading by example (among many: Marie Christine Dussault or Kasia Kulma).
I might get into a more personal motivation in a future blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>